舵がききません！
The rudder isn't working!
（ナルト）ひゃ～！
This is some storm!
すっげえ嵐だってばよ。
（ガイ）このまま潮の流れに
乗っていったら　どうなる？
What's going to happen
if we keep getting swept away
by the current?!
（ヤマト）大丈夫なようです。
It seems like it will be okay.
If we continue like this,
we'll get back on course!
このままいけば
予定航路に出ます。
ハハッ　このまま一気に
雷の国へ行くってばよ！
We're gonna head straight
to the Land of Lightning!
何だ？
What was that?!
What's happening?
何が起こったってばよ？
Here comes another one!
また来るぞ。
起爆札で作られた砲弾か。
Shells made from paper bombs?
That thing's firepower is considerable.
こいつは　かなりの爆発力だ。
（アオバ）いったい　どこから？
Where is it coming from?
あれは…。
Is that...
戦艦？
a battleship?
（ヤマト）違う。
No.
It's an island!
あれは　島だ。
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
Battleship Island
あの島に吸い寄せられていく。
We're being sucked in towards
that island!
Can you change course?!
おい　進路を変えられんのか？
I can't!
The rudder still isn't working!
ダメです。
依然　舵がいうことをききません。
冗談じゃねえってばよ。
You gotta be kidding me!
うあっ！
Naruto!
ナルト！
Wood Style!
木遁！
The ship!
船が…。
The cargo, scrap metal, everything...
Scoop it all up!
（ガタロ）積み荷から　クズ鉄から
何でもすくいあげろ。
Even the humans!
人間だって構わねえ。
ガタロの親分！
Boss Gataro!
I-It's impossible.
ど　どうも　とれ高が…。
The ship should've been blown apart!
船は木っ端みじんに
したはずだろう。
No one returns to the island
unless their net is full!
網いっぱいにするまでは
島には戻らせねえぞ。
いつもどおり　ブツの少ねえ船には→
As usual, a painful experience
lies in wait
for any boat without a full load.
きっつい　お灸が待ってるぜ。
テメエ　俺たちの船をよくも！
Hey you!
How dare you mess with our ship!
ほう…。
あるじゃねえかよ　お宝がよ！
See, there's treasure, after all.
Wha—?!
ハッハッハ！
フン　こんだけ元気なら
市場じゃ　いい値がつくぜ。
A feisty one like you is sure to
bring a good price at auction.
こいつは　ガラクタだがな。
But this is a piece of junk.
よくも額当てを！
Hey, that's my headband!
Open fire!
砲撃開始！　小僧を追い込め！
Corner the brat!
砲撃開始！
Prepare to fire!
座標　左舷１２度　角度２６度　距離５００。
Coordinates: portside 12 degrees,
angle 26 degrees, distance 500.
Fire!
撃て～！
ハッハッハ…　走れ　走れ！
Run, keep running!
やばっ…　うおっ！
Oh no!
W-What is this?!
な…　何だ　これ？
What?!
なにっ！？　バカヤロウ！
You idiots!
That ship hasn't been destroyed yet!
あの船　まだ
くたばってねえじゃねえか！
撃て　撃て　撃ちまくれ！
Fire! Fire! Fire away!
Don't let them get away!
Switch to depth charges!
逃がすな　爆雷に変えろ！
Never mind, just kill them!
こうなりゃ　ヤツら
たたき殺してかまわねえ！
Blast them to smithereens!
木っ端みじんにしろ！
Say...
な…　なんで船が海に潜ってんだ！？
How can the ship dive underwater?
急ごしらえだが
僕の木遁で船体を覆い→
It's hastily made,
but I used my Wood Style to
cover the ship's body
バラストタンクを作って
海水を取り込んで潜水してる。
and improvised a ballast tank
to take in water to keep us
below the surface.
即席の潜水艇だよ。
It's a makeshift submarine.
感知タイプを連れてきて　よかったな。
Thank goodness we brought
a Sensory-Type along.
なんとか爆雷の
到達距離を脱したようです。
We've managed to get
out of range of the depth charges.
（ガイ）このまま潜って→
Can't we stay underwater and
make it out of this region?
領域を脱出することは
できないのか？
Well...
はあ。
この船は　もともと帆船。
Originally, this was a sailing ship.
海に潜ってしまっては
推進力はありません。
It has no power to propel
forward underwater.
今は潮流に乗って
ただ流されているだけなんです。
Right now, the current is
merely pulling us along.
ヘッヘ　この先は水深が浅くなる。
The water depth decreases
beyond this point.
モグラが上がってきたところを
吹っ飛ばしてやる！
When the mole comes up,
I'll blow it to pieces!
この深度を保つ以外に
ないのか？
We have no choice
but to maintain this depth.
So we can't surface again?
浮上も　引き返すことも
できないってか。
ダハッ！
浸水だ！
防げ！
It's flooding!
Plug it up!
Stop!
止まれ！
１２時の方向　ほぼ真下！
Towards twelve o'clock!
There's a current of air directly
below on the ocean bottom!
海底に空気の流れあり！
侵入できます！
We can go through!
Everyone, run up to the front!
みんな　前方に走れ！
わあ！
プハ！
That was a close one.
間一髪だった。
ここってば。
Where are we?
（ヤマト）ああ　どうやら。
（ガイ）海底洞窟か。
It looks like...
An underwater cavern?
奥にまだ
いくつかトンネルがあるようだ。
There are more tunnels further in.
位置的にここは
あの島の地下ですね。
As for our location,
we must be beneath the island.
Stairs.
階段。
This cavern seems to have
been excavated for human use.
この洞窟は
人為的に掘られたもののようです。
だったら地上に通じる手段も
あるかもしれない。
Then, there could be a way
to get to the surface.
Let's split up and check.
じゃあ　手分けして調べるか。
ナルト　どこへ行く？
Naruto! Where are you going?!
アイツんとこ戻って→
I'm going back to get my headband!
額当てを取り返す！
あのなあ！
Hold it!
Didn't I tell you?
言っただろう
今　海にあがるのは→
Going back to the surface
right now means certain death.
死にに行くようなものだ。
That headband is important to me!
あの額当ては　俺の大事な。
You will get it back!
You definitely will.
取り返す。
もちろんだよ。
でも今は　ここで身を隠して
次のチャンスを待つんだ。
But for now, we'll stay hidden
and wait for our chance.
それに　僕も。
Besides, I think...
木遁を使いすぎたようだ。
I used my Wood Style too much.
しばらく休めば
大丈夫だよ。
I'll be fine once I rest a bit.
Captain Yamato...
ヤマト隊長。
うわっ　アチチ！！
H-Hot?!
おっ　温泉だってばよ
ヤマト隊長！
It's a hot spring, Captain Yamato!
え？
We can easily replenish
our chakra by resting here.
ここでしっかり休んでりゃ
チャクラなんてすぐ戻るよ。
はあ～　確かに
いい湯だ。
You're right.
This water feels great!
（ガイ）ワチャー！
これは…。
What is this?
う～ん…。
It seems these people
were the islanders.
この人たちは
あの島の島民だったらしい。
Islanders? You mean they were
with those pirates?
島民？　海賊の仲間か。
No. It seems they were
the indigenous people of this island.
いや　どうやら　もともとこの島に
住んでいた人たちのようだ。
What's going on?
どういうことだってばよ？
Several decades ago those pirates
attacked the island
十数年前に
あの海賊が島を襲ってきて→
and it's written here that
the native islanders were slaughtered.
島民たちは虐殺されたと
書いてある。
な　何だって？
What?
((島民たち：うわぁ～！))
（アオバ）この人たちは→
These people got away
by going underground
山にある坑道をおりて
地下に逃げ込み→
through a tunnel in the mountain
and hiding themselves.
ずっと隠れていたらしい。
ハハハッ　走れ走れ！
Run, run!
ヤツらの船があがってくるまで
せいぜい俺を楽しませろ！
I want to be entertained
until their boat surfaces!
もうちょっと耐えろや。
Just grin and bear it!
The next boat with the lowest yield,
come on out!
次　２番目にあがりの少ねえ船
出てこいや！
地上は
あの海賊たちに占拠され→
The pirates occupy the land above.
If these people were discovered,
it meant certain death.
見つかれば命はないということか。
That's why...
だから　ここで…。
They lived down here
quietly for decades?
十数年も　ひっそりと
暮らしてたってわけか。
How sad.
かわいそうにな。
どうした？
What're you doing?
みんなの無念　このうずまきナルトが
しっかり受け取ったぜ。
I, Naruto Uzumaki, will get justice
for their pain and suffering!
俺ってば　やっぱり　もう一度→
Looks like I have no choice
but to see that guy again.
アイツに会わなくちゃ
いけなくなった。
この坑道から入ってきたのか。
So they used this tunnel.
It's no good.
The line is frayed and doesn't work.
ダメだ　ワイヤーがちぎれてて
作動しない。
火山の噴火口か。
It's a volcanic crater.
It's quite a ways to the top.
上までは相当な高さだな。
フゥ～。
おっ　何だ？　あったかい。
Hey, how come it's so warm?
It seems there's a subterranean
hot spring stream.
どうやら　この下には
温泉の水脈があるようですね。
Yeah, there is!
あったあった。　さっきまで
ヤマト隊長が浸かってたよ。
Captain Yamato was taking
a soak until a while ago.
かなり大きい。
It's quite large.
W-What's the matter, Naruto?
おい　何を力んでる？
温泉　浮かぶ…。
Hot springs... floating...
Wood... Wood Style... Submarine?!
木　木遁　潜水艇…。
I got it!
わかった！
どうした？　ナルト。
What is it, Naruto?
笑わないで聞いてくれよ。
Just hear me out.
Don't laugh, okay?
How about this strategy?
こんな作戦は　どうかな？
（みんな）ハハハハ！
ダメかな？
No good?
いや　やってみよう！
No, let's try it.
♪～
ハァ…。
おい　ナルト！
ヘヘヘ！　大丈夫だってばよ！
Hey Naruto!
I'm okay!
よ～し！　出航だってばよ！
All right! Let's sail!
ゲキマユ先生！　頼むぜ！
おう！
Bushy Brow Sensei! You're on!
Right! You got it!
よっしゃ～っ！
この感じは…。
How was that?
やっぱり　出るわきゃ…。
I guess it was imposs...
ん？
Hot!
あち～っ！
– All right! Float upwards!
– Way to go!
おっしゃ！
Just you wait, you pirates!
待ってろよ！　海賊ども！
（海賊たち）うわぁ～！
ハハハ！
ガタロの親分　さすがに　ヤツら→
Boss Gataro!
Maybe those guys died
at the bottom of the sea.
海の底で　おっ死んじまったんじゃ
ねえっすか？
No sense in waiting any longer.
これ以上　待ってても…。
うわっ！
俺に　意見しようってのか！
Are you telling me what to do?!
あの小僧が
簡単にくたばるかよ！
That kid's not gonna die that easily.
殺すと決めたら　徹底的にやる！
I decided to kill him and
I'm gonna do a thorough job of it.
島を　ぶんどったときのようにな。
Just like the time I took over this island.
な　な　何が起こった？
W-What just happened?!
おりゃっ！
あの小僧！
Damn that brat!
もういっちょ！
One more!
砲撃中止！　暴発するぞ！
Stop firing or it'll explode!
おのれ～っ！
Damn that...
ヘヘヘ！　どんなもんだい！
How's that?!
や　ヤツを　ヤツを捕まえろ！
G-Get him!
逃がしやがったら
全員　叩き殺すぞ！
If you let him escape,
you're all dead!
ヘヘヘ！　アハハ！
囲め！　袋のドブネズミにしろ！
Surround him!
Catch him like a rat in a mousetrap!
負けるかよ！
I'm not gonna lose!
この島にいた人たちの
恨みを晴らさせてもらうぞ！
This is retribution for
all the islanders' suffering!
ふざけるな！
この島は俺のものだ。
Are you kidding?
This island is mine!
ガタガタぬかすと　テメエたちも
ヤツらのように皆殺しにしてやる！
If you make trouble,
I'll kill you all the same way
I killed the others!
待てよ　他のヤツらは？
Wait a minute.
Where are your friends?
お前たちこそ
グッチャン　グッチャンにしてやる！
You're the one
who's gonna get pulverized!
この！
Why you...
チッ　分身か。
Clones, eh?
Over here! Over here!
こっちだ　こっち！
くっ！
あれは…。
What's that?!
あっ！
海賊ども　覚悟しやがれ！
Hey, you pirates!
Get ready for this!
Wood Style!
木遁！
いけ！
Go!
なに！？
飛べ！
Fly!
ぐわぁ～！！
All right!
よっしゃあ！
恨みは晴らしたぜ。
I have avenged you.
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokyuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
dance dance dance to you
just just just to you
akai itode tsunagacchattenda
We're connected by the Red String of Fate
dareka ga dareka wo damashite achichi
Somebody is doing something
burning hot by deceiving somebody
sonna de iinoka?
Are you OK with that?
ore wa chigauze baka ni sunjanee
I'm not like them. You don't know the first thing about me
kitanai kirei giragira no sora
The dirty, beautiful sky glitters
antanimo mieterunokai?
Can you see it too?
hageshiku aishi aisareta koto wa arunokai?
Have you ever loved, and been loved, passionately?
ore to anta no kizuna wa dounatterundai?
What's become of our bond?
c'mon!
haato dokyun de bachibachi sunzen
My heart is thumping and about to explode
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! aini mudawanee!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Love is it!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Next Episode
Hey Aoba, is this really the island?
Well, judging from the direction it flew off to,
（くもじい）
もしもし　そこのあなた。
we can safely say this is its habitat.
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
To think that there was a bird that could fly off with Guy Sensei.
We have to look for him quickly!
今日は→
Wait! There's someone there!
I'll go talk to them. You guys continue the search.
超有名観光スポットの→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: The Forgotten Island
ふだんは入れない
裏側を探検するぞ。
The Forgotten Island
Wait! Just who are you?
え？　動物園に戦国武将のお墓！？
さぁ　わしらと一緒に
大空を飛んでみませんか？